Guide to the Frick Fine Arts Department Chair Records, 1920-1986 UA.90.8.16.2
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- William C. Loerke, 1959-1974; II.
  - Wadsworth, Frank W. - Dean, Division of the Humanities, 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 57)
- Donald E. Gordon, 1968-1971; III.
  Donald Gordon (1931-1984) succeeded Loerke as Chairman of the Fine Arts Department, serving from 1969 to 1973.
  Gordon obtained his bachelors, masters and doctorate degrees from Harvard University. Before coming to the University of Pittsburgh, Gordon served as the chairman of the Department of Fine Arts at Dickinson College in Carlisle, PA, from 1961 to 1969. His research focused on Expressionist art, particularly German artist Ernst Kirchner for whom he authored a catalogue raisonne. After stepping down as department chair, Gordon served as teaching faculty in the Frick Fine Arts Department until he died of cancer in 1984.
  This series contains correspondence pertaining to applicants for the Mellon Visiting Professorship in the Frick Fine Arts Department, as well as other prospective faculty.
  - Ettlinger, L.D. - Prospective Mellon Professor, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Gazda, Elaine - Prospective Faculty, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Gombrich, Ernst - Prospective Mellon Professor, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Mellon Professorship, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Prospective Faculty, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Prospective Faculty, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Regional Council for International Education (RCIE) Graduate Art Study Program, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Schefold, Karl - Prospective Mellon Professor, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Shearman, John - Prospective Mellon Professor, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Von Simson, Otto - Prospective Mellon Professor, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 67)
- John Williams and Katheryn Linduff, 1981-1986; IV.
  John Williams (1928 -2015) joined the faculty of the University of Pittsburgh Frick Fine Arts Department in 1972, serving as chair of the department from 1978 to 1984. From 1997 until his retirement in 2000 he served as the Andrew W. Mellon Professor of History of Art and Architecture. Williams earned his bachelor's degree from Yale before earning his M.A. and Ph.D. from the University of Michigan. From 1960 to 1972 Williams taught Medieval Spanish Art History at Swarthmore College. Late in his career, Williams published the five volume Illustrated Beatus: A Corpus of the Illustrations of the Commentary on the Apocalypse. Among his many honors, Williams was named a Fellow of the Medieval Academy of America in 2008.
  Katheryn Linduff joined the faculty of the Frick Fine Arts Department in 1971 while pursuing her Ph.D. from the University of Pittsburgh, which she earned in 1972. She served as chair of the department from 1985 to 1989. Prior to teaching at Pitt, she had earned her bachelor's degree from Dickinson College and her master's degree from the University of Pittsburgh. Linduff is an expert in Early China and has published on topics like gender and metallurgy as they relate to Chinese art and archaeology.
  Scope and Contents Notes
  This series contains correspondence and reports pertaining to the administration and activities of the Frick Fine Arts Library while John Williams and Katheryn Linduff were department chairs from 1978 to 1984 and 1985 to 1989, respectively. Included are library annual reports and information about the library collection and staffing.
  - Frick Fine Arts Library, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Frick Fine Arts Library, 1981-1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Frick Fine Arts Library, 1983-1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Frick Fine Arts Library, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Frick Fine Arts Library, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Frick Fine Arts Library, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Graduate Student Files, 1930-1970; V.
  This series contains correspondence and transcripts of prospective and enrolled graduate students in the Frick Fine Arts Department.
  Access Restrictions
  Due to the confidential nature of these records, files in this series are closed for a period of 75 years from the time of their creation.
  - Graduate Student Transcripts, 1930-1939 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Student Transcripts, 1937-1960 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Graduate Student Transcripts, 1940-1949 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Graduate Student Transcripts, 1960-1963 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Graduate Student Transcripts, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Graduate Student Records, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 12)